<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Gustav Olsson</title>
    <link>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Gustav Olsson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 21:55:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello! (New website in 2020)</title>
      <link>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/hello-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 21:38:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/hello-2020/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to yet another website&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan the world around you using turn3d!</title>
      <link>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/turn3d-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 21:26:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/turn3d-release/</guid>
      <description>I just released my latest app, turn3d. turn3d enables you to 3d scan the world around you using only a semi-modern iOS device. Check it out here!
*{padding:0;margin:0;overflow:hidden}html,body{height:100%}img,span{position:absolute;top:0;bottom:0;width:100%;margin:auto;}span{height:1.5em;text-align:center;font:60px/1.5 sans-serif;color:white;text-shadow:0 0 0.5em black;}▶&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seaside Racing Remastered (Windows/macOS/Linux)</title>
      <link>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/seaside-racing-remastered/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/seaside-racing-remastered/</guid>
      <description>After getting an email from yet another person who enjoyed the original Seaside Racing back when it was released on the Xbox 360 in 2010, I decided to start working on a PC port last summer. After a few months of part-time work, it is finally done!
Check it out on itch.io here: seasideracing.se
The gameplay should be exactly the same as the original and the graphics a bit better. The Xbox avatars have been replaced by my own set of randomly generated characters that look just mad enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laser Scanner Prototype</title>
      <link>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/laser-scanner-prototype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/laser-scanner-prototype/</guid>
      <description>For the last couple of weeks, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a custom laser scanner design. Basically, a laser scanner is a device that uses 2 mirrors to direct a laser beam to a specific point in space and it can, when moving fast enough, be used to draw geometric patterns onto some planar surface. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m interested in building a laser scanner is that they&amp;rsquo;re a fundamental component of many CNC machines such as high-end 3d printers (based on the Selective Laser Sintering (SLS) or Stereolithography (SLA) techniques) or etching machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello! (New website in 2015)</title>
      <link>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/hello-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gustavolsson.github.io/blog/hello-2015/</guid>
      <description>When I moved to the new site, I decided not to have a blog because I wanted to focus on making things instead writing updates. What I&amp;rsquo;ve realized is that there is a point to summarizing and publishing a log entry of what I work on from time to time. It helps me see the progress that I&amp;rsquo;m making more clearly and it also gives me time to think through the decisions I make along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>